Let me tell you a story about my past.
It was back when I was in sixth grade.
One of the girls in my class brought a box
with around seven or eight hamsters to me.
She'd carelessly let them breed...
...and had no idea what to do
since she couldn't keep them all.
I took them home,
filled a large wine bottle with water,
and dropped them all in it.
When I returned to my room
after dinner three hours later,
I was fascinated by what I saw.
One of the hamsters had managed to stay alive
by standing on the other lifeless corpses.
It honestly gave me goosebumps.
I decided to keep it and named it Spice.
What I saw reminded me of
the short story, "The Spider's Thread."
Have you heard of it?
A sinner named Kandata was a cold-blooded
criminal who'd been sent to Hell,
but he had performed one act of compassion
in his life by sparing a spider's life.
Moved by it, Buddha lowers
a spider's thread from Paradise to Hell.
Kandata begins climbing it to Paradise,
but he kicks off all the other sinners
who tried to follow him.
At that moment, the thread breaks,
casting him back down to the depths of Hell.
You might not believe this, but I'll tell you anyway.
Actually, you might understand.
Ever since I met Spice,
I've started seeing spider's threads
every now and then.
I've killed anyone I've seen
with one dangling above their head.
But this one time, a boy foiled my plans.
And then, a spider's thread
appeared above his head, too.
Yashiro!
I know what lies in your future!
But the boy didn't die.
I named him Spice and decided to observe him.
That's you, Satoru.
That will be 987 yen.
Thank you.
Come to think of it,
didn't Satoru mention this one time?
You can actually take a direct train to Ueno.
It's true.
Just why did he say that?
Good morning, Satoru!
Yeah, this is quite remarkable.
You don't seem like you spent
fifteen years in a coma.
Fifteen... years...
Wow, you can speak already?
Looks like you'll be able
to begin rehabilitation soon.
For fifteen whole years, Mom spent
four hours every day taking care of my body.
And for the last three years,
she's been using something called
an EMS device to prepare for the day I woke up.
She kept my joints and muscles in shape.
I was 139 cm tall back in fifth grade,
but now I am 169 cm tall.
Dr. Kitamura kept alternating between
"This is all thanks to your mother"
and "I can't believe this" over and over.
All right, Satoru-kun. I think it's about time.
Answer this question.
What's the last thing you remember
from before you fell into the coma?
The last thing I remember...
Huh?
What happened, again?
Those memories had been
locked up tightly behind a closed door.
Do you want to see yourself?
You're taking it in stride, huh?
I mean, your face must look a lot different
from when you were eleven.
But well, considering how
your memories are all jumbled up,
maybe you're still having trouble
zeroing in on your own identity.
At first, I accepted his words at face value,
but the term "Heisei era",
which I should've never seen before,
didn't seem at all unfamiliar.
"Endure."
"Heart rate monitor."
"Feeling of loss."
"Arbitration."
I can read all these words.
Just when did I learn them?
What's with me?
Good morning, Satoru.
Morning.
You have visitors.
Long time no see, Satoru.
You seem well, Satoru-kun.
Kobayashi Kenya and Sugita Hiromi
were two classmates of mine I was close to.
Kenya had become a lawyer, and Hiromi a doctor.
I had fun talking to them
about the most pointless things.
Kenya looked like he wanted to ask me something,
but I think Mom had told him to tread carefully.
So we ended up just chatting that day.
Laters.
There were a lot of questions
I wanted to ask them, too,
but it seemed like Mom was trying to
prevent me from talking about my past.
Mom had been living solely
for my sake for fifteen years,
holding onto the belief I would awaken someday.
If she doesn't want me to remember,
then maybe I don't have to.
Are you okay?
Shall we call it a day?
Satoru!
Congratulations, Kayo.
I got married. I'm Sugita Kayo now.
Oh, so Hiromi's the father?
Yeah.
I knew he wanted to say something to me.
I guess it was about you and your child.
Probably.
Come to think of it,
the baby has Hiromi's long eyelashes.
Yeah, even though he's a boy.
His name's Mirai.
Mirai... "Future," huh?
That's a great name.
Satoru...
Honestly, we didn't know if it was right
for us to find happiness by ourselves.
I mean, it could've been our fault
that you ended up in a coma.
It kind of felt like...
we were leaving you behind.
Kayo, I hold my fate in my own hands.
You don't have to feel guilty about anything.
I'm sure I am who I am right now
as a result of my own choices.
For a guy who spent fifteen years in a coma,
you've still got a way with words.
But you know what, Satoru?
Before, I could only ever picture
a life of solitude for myself,
but now I have a family to call my own.
And it's all because you were there for me.
Thank you.
"Thank you," huh?
What did I do?
There, there! Hungry, are we?
There, there.
Satoru? Are you all right?
Yeah.
Sorry for springing all this on you at once.
Must've worn you out.
Bye. I'll come visit you again.
Sure. Laters.
Oh, you're back already?
Yeah.
Hinazuki dropped by earlier.
Yeah, I ran into her too.
Her baby's adorable, isn't he?
Say, Mom...
What is it?
They're here again?!
Who is?
Gossip magazine photographers.
They want to cover your story now that
you've awoken from a fifteen-year coma.
Oh, right.
You were saying something?
Nah. Never mind.
Come in.
Hello.
Thank you for doing this.
When will I be able to walk again, Dr. Kitamura?
I couldn't say. It's all up to you.
Then double my rehab regimen from today.
I want to walk outside as soon as possible.
I'll consider it.
Excuse me.
Yes. Thank you, Director.
He's making a steady recovery.
He could regain his memories anytime now.
No.
Like I said the other day,
I'll have to turn you down.
My patient isn't some guinea pig—
Goodbye.
That's great, Satoru-kun!
Your limbs have gotten a lot stronger.
Congrats, Satoru-kun!
You're amazing, Fujinuma-san!
I can't believe you went the distance!
Great job hanging in there.
Kenya-kun's here to see you, Satoru.
Hey, Kenya.
Sorry for coming so late.
Nah. Thanks for coming.
Hello, Satoru-kun.
Nice to meet you.
I used to work with your mother.
We've met several times before
you started elementary school.
Come on, that was more than twenty years ago!
There's no way he'd remember.
Bye. I'll come again.
Take care.
We've waited fifteen long years.
What's the point of rushing now?
Let's take it slow and steady.
Right.
Hello.
Oh...
So you're having surgery in two weeks, Kumi-chan.
Onee-chan's giving me this "bone marrow" thing.
They say it'll cure me.
But I'm scared.
Is it true you were asleep for fifteen years?
You've been here around three months, huh?
Yep.
I've been doing my best
so I'd look good in front of you.
If you're gone, I'll lose all motivation.
Courage...
Want me to teach you how to muster up courage?
Picture the smiles of the people you care about.
With a smile on your face too, of course.
"A drifter in time.
Man who wakes up after
fifteen-year coma still likes little girls.
Adult in body, child at heart.
He gets discharged soon!"
How's that for a story?
Nice.
Secretly photographing
civilians on hospital grounds,
libel, and trespassing.
More than enough to get you punished by law.
Get out of here right now.
That flower was really pretty.
Oh, Nishizono-san!
Hello!
Hey, Kumi-chan.
Fujinuma Satoru-kun...
Y-Yes?
It's me. Did you forget?
Well, I guess I have changed a lot myself.
Look. I'm your homeroom teacher from fifth grade...
Yashiro Gaku.
I go by Nishizono now.
I also changed my first name to Manabu.
Why did you change your name?
I got married five years ago and was adopted
into my wife's family as a son-in-law.
My father-in-law had been a city councilor for ages,
but he passed away three years ago.
I inherited his constituency
and became a councilor myself.
That's when I switched to the more
common reading of my name.
So you're a politician now?
Yeah, but I'm still in my first year.
But I think you'll make for
a fine politician, Yashiro-sensei.
I met Kumi-chan at a charity event for leukemia.
I happen to know one of this hospital's
directors, so I referred her here.
Is that so?
I found out that you had regained
consciousness much earlier,
but it took me this long to come visit you.
You came all the way to see me today?
I'd been eagerly waiting for you
to wake for fifteen years.
Thank you.
Hey, we went through a lot together.
Sorry, I...
Yeah, I heard.
You haven't regained all your memories yet, right?
You can regain them one step at a time.
Hey.
Oh, Yashiro-sensei.
Are you going to see Kumi-chan too?
Yes. I heard that her surgery's
the day after tomorrow,
so today's the last day she can have visitors.
Yeah. I just saw her myself.
That said, she was fast asleep, so I couldn't talk to her.
Oh...
Maybe I should come back later, then.
Since you're here, mind chatting for a bit?
Sure, but we don't want
the paparazzi interrupting us.
Why don't we go someplace quieter?
In fact, I know the perfect place.
You didn't know about this elevator, did you?
This is a bit like an adventure, isn't it?
Press the roof button for me, would you?
That's a shame.
On a clear day, we'd get to see a beautiful
sunset from here right about now.
Still, no sketchy photographers will come up here.
This place is technically off-limits,
so keep this a secret.
Reminds me of how you, Kenya, Hiromi, and the rest
always talked about going to your secret "hideout."
Yashiro.
I've regained...
my memories!